The phantom Pokémon Mew...
They say it’s extinct,
but even in recent times,
there have been reported sightings of Mew.
Unconfirmed sightings.
Yes...
Nobody’s ever gotten
a single good photo of it.
Unfortunately true.
This is Mew.
Some say it possesses divine power,
with which it caused a cataclysmic flood...
Others say it made crops grow in barren land,
to share them with the people.
Is it an angel, or a demon?
Or is it just capricious?
Whatever the case,
it undoubtedly wields great power.
This is the fossil we just excavated
on our latest expedition.
A part of Mew’s body...
Or so we believe.
Let’s bring it back
to the laboratory at once.
If it truly is a Mew fossil...
Yeah...
We may be able to create
the mightiest Pokémon.
What is this place?
Who am I?
Who are you?
I...
...cannot forget the world
that being flew off to.
Who am I?
Why am I here?
No...
I simply am here.
As of yet...
...I have not been born
into this world.
Mewtwo is finally awake!
“Mewtwo”...?
Telepathy?
Mewtwo. That’s you.
We created you from
the Pokémon said to be rarest in the world!
Indeed...
Behold the rarest
Pokémon in the world:
Mew!
“Mew”...?
Is that my progenitor?
My father?
My mother?
In a sense, but not quite.
You were based off Mew,
but created to be much stronger!
By whom?
You say neither a father,
nor a mother...
So then by God?
Is God the one who created me?
The only beings capable of creating life in this world
are God and humans.
So it was you?
Humans created me?
This is a scientific triumph!
We finally have proof
that we were right!
We can continue our research!
Let’s start on the next model!
Congratulations!
We finally did it!
Who am I?
What is this place?
What was the purpose
of my birth?
Creating the mightiest Pokémon
in the world...
That was our dream...
Is this power my own?
Am I truly the mightiest
Pokémon in the world?
Mew...
Am I stronger than you?
You may very well be
the mightiest Pokémon in the world...
But there exists something else in this world
that is just as powerful.
Humans?
If you join forces with us humans,
the world will be ours.
The world will be ours...?
But if your power
is left unchecked,
the world will be brought
to its knees.
You must control your power.
“Control”?
Are you content to rely on brute strength alone
and allow the world to burn like you have this island?
What should I do?
Restraining my power with this armor
that protects my being...
What is it that
you want me to do?
It’s simple, really.
Just do as everyone else
has done on this planet.
Everyone?
Fight, destroy, and plunder.
The strong succeed here.
But even so, who am I?
Where am I?
For what purpose do I fight?
Why am I alive?
You’re a Pokémon.
Pokémon live for humans;
to be used by them.
So you mean to say
I should fight for you?
That I should fight for humans?
You’re a Pokémon
created by humans.
What other worth could you have?
“Worth”?
Who am I?
Why am I alive?
What are you doing?!
Do you intend to defy humankind?
Humans may have created me...
But I am no human...
As an artificial creation,
I am not even a true Pokémon!
Who am I?
What is this place?
Who asked that I be born?
Who wished for my creation?
I resent everything
that led to my birth.
So this...
...is neither an attack,
nor a declaration of war...
It is me striking back at
that which has created me.
This young man is
Satoshi from Masara Town.
Aiming to become a Pokémon Master,
he trains hard while journeying with his friends.
I can smell the ocean!
Nice view, too.
How about we stop for lunch?
All right!
I’m so hungry...
You sure stuffed yourself at
the Pokémon Center this morning, though.
That was then,
and this is now!
One can’t battle
on an empty stomach.
Eating is part of training, too!
Got that right!
You’re the man, Takeshi!
You’ve really got a way with words!
Help us set out
the dishes and cutlery, okay?
Sure, I got this!
I can’t...
Satoshi! We’re not done yet!
I’m so hungry I can’t move
a muscle...
Sheesh!
Kasumi.
Gently simmer...
Slowly nurture...
Stew and Pokémon training alike
can’t be rushed.
Hey! My homeboy!
You’re the homie from Masara Town named Satoshi
who got eight Badges, am I right?
Yeah. Why?
Okay!
Can you battle with your Pokémon?
I can’t say no to a good battle!
What happened to
not moving a muscle?
I can make room for
a Pokémon Battle or two before breakfast!
Except in this case
it’s before lunch...
tatoe hi no naka mizu no naka kusa no naka mori no naka
Be it fire, water, grass, or forests,
tsuchi no naka kumo no naka ano ko no sukaato no naka (kyaah!)
the ground, the clouds, or under that girl's skirt (Eek!)
naka naka naka naka naka naka naka naka taihen dakedo
It's really, really, really, really hard to handle,
kanarazu getto da ze pokemon getto daze
but I'm gonna get them all! I'm gonna get Pokémon!
masara taun ni sayonara bye bye
Masara Town, I bid you goodbye
ore wa koitsu to tabi ni deru (Pikachu!)
I'm going on a journey with this little guy (Pikachu!)
kitaeta waza de kachimakuri
I'll win each battle with the moves I've mastered,
nakama o fuyashite tsugi no machi e
then head to the next town and make friends along the way!
itsumo itsu demo umaku yuku nante
There's no way to know for sure
hoshou wa doko ni mo nai kedo (sorya sou ja!)
if things will always work out (Got that right!)
itsu demo itsumo honki de ikiteru koitsu tachi ga iru
But with my companions by my side, we'll live life to the fullest!
tatoe hi no naka mizu no naka kusa no naka mori no naka
Be it fire, water, grass, or forests,
tsuchi no naka kumo no naka ano ko no sukaato no naka (shitsukoi!)
the ground, the clouds, or under that girl's skirt (Knock it off!)
naka naka naka naka naka naka naka naka taihen dakedo
It's really, really, really, really hard to handle,
kanarazu getto da ze pokemon getto daze
but I'm gonna get them all! I'm gonna get Pokémon!
tatakai tsukarete oyasumi good night
Weary from battling, I bid you goodnight
mabuta o tojireba yomigaeru (Pikachu?)
When I close my eyes, I'm taken back (Pikachu?)
honoo ga moete kaze ga mai
to the roaring fire, the dancing wind,
nakigoe todoroku ano batoru ga
and the echoing shouts of that battle
kinou no teki wa kyou no tomo tte
"Yesterday's foe is today's ally"
furui kotoba ga aru kedo (furui to wa nan ja!)
According to some old saying (What do you mean "Old"?!)
kyou no tomo wa ashita no tomodachi sou sa eien ni
But an ally made today is my friend tomorrow, and will be forevermore
aa akogare no pokemon masutaa ni
Ah, I want to be a Pokémon Master so bad
naritai na naranakucha zettai natte yaru
I wanna be one! Gotta be one! Will be one!
Why?! Oh my God!
We did it!
His opponent was weak,
that’s all.
His Pokémon weren’t well raised.
Pikachu shines brighter by the day!
He’s dazzling!
We members of Team Rocket
gotta get that Pikachu at all costs, meow!
But just look at that...
Here, Togepi. Open wide!
Like it?
I’m starving, meow...
I have a frying pan.
Yeah, but without any meat or vegetables,
a pan’s just a slab of iron, meow.
Satoshi from Masara Town...
...as well as his traveling companions:
The Hanada Gym Leader, Kasumi
and the Nibi Gym Leader, Takeshi.
Master, shall I extend an invitation
to them as well?
Understood.
Who are you?
What’s that about?!
Stop it!
Typical Lizardon.
But...
Is this for me?
Please pardon the sudden letter.
What a pretty lady!
Having recognized you as
promising Pokémon Trainers,
my master, the mightiest Pokémon Trainer,
has formally invited you to his party.
It will be held in
the Pokémon castle on New Island.
Please check the appropriate box on the reply card
indicating whether or not you will be present.
We hope you will accept this invitation
from the mightiest Pokémon Trainer.
The pretty lady...
What should we do?
Let’s go! We gotta do it!
Feels pretty good to be called
promising or whatever!
So, you’re gonna check the box
on the reply card?
Definitely!
You’re not going bye-bye
without saying hi to us first, are you?
What’s this?
Calm down, Ratta!
Kingler, enough already!
The weather was so nice, too!
The weather by the sea
is always fickle.
What?
The ferry’s not coming?
We can’t go to New Island?
We’re lucky we
were even invited!
Quiet down, everyone!
The woman standing next to me
is in charge of this wharf.
I’m Voyager.
If you wish to know the sea,
ask the Camome by the wharf.
Though you need not bother.
Simply follow the path of the wind.
I’ve never witnessed such a hurricane.
It’s that bad?
I grew up by the port,
yet I’ve never seen such a raging storm.
Worse yet, the eye of the storm is offshore
above the skies of New Island.
I simply cannot subject you all
to such peril.
As the protector of this port,
that is my wish.
There you have it.
The ferry is canceled.
I’ll be just fine with my Pokémon!
It’s good in the water.
We’ll cross the ocean,
no problem!
Please, wait.
I know the ocean,
and I’m telling you no.
That’s right!
Besides, if your Pokémon
were injured,
you’d have no way of getting them treated
at the Pokémon Center right now!
What do you mean?
Ms. Joy from the Pokémon Center
went missing a week ago.
We can’t treat any Pokémon’s injuries
without her.
That missing person poster
over there is for her.
She’s pretty!
Huh?
She looks... familiar...
Stop!
Stop or you’re under arrest!
Sheesh!
I suppose trying to stop them
was a fool’s errand.
What?
They’re Pokémon Trainers,
after all...
Adventurers.
If they were the sort of people to quit after being told no,
they wouldn’t have gathered here.
Let us pray for their safety.
The mightiest trainer is
waiting across the sea!
I can’t back down now!
But there’s no way we can
cross the raging sea with our Pokémon.
You’re right...
The smashing, crashing, stormy sea...
...is nothing for our group of three!
Our lot were bathed in the crashing waves of
the Guren Strait as newborns!
You said it, meow!
If one of us were ever in need,
we’d come together so they’d succeed!
The horizon in the distance...
...beckons us ashore!
Wanna ride?
Not saying it’s gonna be free,
but we could be convinced
to give you a ride.
Yeah! We’d appreciate it!
Our ship has come in... Literally!
Togepi, stay still just a bit longer.
But will we really make it
in a boat like this?
Don’t judge a book by its cover!
A clever Pidgeot conceals its talons!
Captain, we’re good to go!
Roger!
And... push, meow!
It’s you guys!
Team Rocket!
You really don’t let up!
What do you want?
If you ask us
“What do you want?”,
We’ll answer out of—
Satoshi! Kasumi!
Where are Satoshi and Pikachu?
I can’t tell!
Thank you, Hitodeman.
Zenigame,
you really saved me!
We’re delighted you could make it.
Please present your invitation.
This message is to confirm that
these people are among those invited.
I knew it was you!
What?
The Ms. Joy I saw at the port!
They do kinda look alike.
What do you mean?
I’ve been in service of this castle
since I was born.
If you would,
please come with me.
Our other esteemed guests
have already arrived.
Phew...
The trainers over there
are the ones who arrived before you.
Only three of them?
When there were so many
at the port?
The invitations given to the trainers who
could not brave the storm were wasted.
Are you saying the storm
was a test?
Please release your Pokémon from their
Monster Balls and take a seat.
You are chosen trainers.
So, if we want to sneak our way
into the castle...
...we’ll just have to
take the exit, won’t we?
What exit?
Down there.
The sewage pipes?!
I’m not some lousy rat!
Quit whining!
It’s the only way in,
so deal with it!
What’s up?
Nothing...
Come on, let’s go!
Slide, slide...
So you guys made it here, too?
Did you all cross through the ocean?
I flew here.
My Pidgeot glides
right through hurricanes.
Say hi, you guys!
I crossed the ocean
on my Gyarados’s back.
Gyarados is the Atrocious Pokémon, right?
Yup.
I came here with this little one,
and with them as well.
Beautiful...
Kamex, Dugong, Rafflesia,
Kyukon, Gallop...
And your Pukurin, too.
But above all...
You, their lovely trainer,
are truly a queen of incomparable beauty!
Miss, once this storm has passed,
you and I will look upon the tranquil sea, enjoy my specially made rice balls,
and discuss our—
All right, you.
You can eat on your own.
Esteemed guests,
I apologize for the wait.
The mightiest Pokémon Trainer
will be with you shortly.
What’s that?
Nyarth!
Oh, coming, meow!
Indeed...
The person before you is
the mightiest Pokémon Trainer,
as well as the mightiest Pokémon.
Master Mewtwo.
Mewtwo...?
A Pokémon who’s
a Pokémon Trainer?!
Yeah right!
Is that wrong?
This voice!
It’s telepathy!
I set my own rules.
If this is some kinda sick joke,
I’m outta here!
Go, Gyarados!
Gyarados,
use Destroyer Beam!
Gyarados!
Much too easy.
I have no further need of you.
Ms. Joy, I knew it was you!
Where am I?
What am I doing here?
I brought you here from the Pokémon Center
so that you could care for me.
Having a doctor who is familiar
with Pokémon anatomy is convenient.
You’ve proven your worth.
Though you surely
have no memory of it.
What was that?!
With my powers, I can easily
control you humans however I see fit.
That’s horrible!
What’s this place?
None of this looks
like treasure, does it?
What a cutie, meow!
You call that cute?
This was how our research began.
This device was designed to
create copies of Pokémon.
Through this device,
we have at last...
...successfully realized that goal.
Wh-What?!
Nyarth!
Nyarth?!
H-H-Hey, wait!
Hey, Kojirou! Get him!
Help me, meow!
Grab on!
M-My fur... My fur!
Oh! Three strands of fur!
Even a small sample will do...
By studying the composition of
the Pokémon in question...
...we should be able to create
a copy of the original Pokémon.
Who’s this?
Nyarth!
Nyarth?!
I’m Nyarth, meow!
Then, is this...?
A copy of Nyarth?
Aww geez...
But the copy we created
was no mere copy.
Deep in the j— gle, we discovered
a ruin built to worship Mew.
There, we found
a fossilized Mew eyelash.
We created Mewtwo based on
the composition of the fossil.
To create the world’s
mightiest Pokémon...
That was our dream.
However...
So this is...
...a Pokémon copy laboratory?!
But...
Why’s nobody here, meow?
Maybe they have the day off?
Or they could be on vacation...
I had once hoped to work
with you humans.
Yet your kind failed me.
Humans are the lowest of creatures,
beneath even Pokémon.
If weak, heartless beings like you humans
control the planet...
...then we’re all doomed.
You want your kind— Pokémon—
to rule the planet?!
Pokémon cannot, either.
Because this planet is already
controlled by humans.
There are even Pokémon who
live for humans!
What?
You say you’re not a slave?
You stay with your trainer
out of mutual affinity?
That very act was a grave mistake.
Pikachu!
Weak Pokémon
nestle up to humans.
Satoshi, are you okay?
Yeah.
How dare you hurt Pikachu?!
You may be strong,
but there’s no Pokémon that can’t be caught!
Go, my Saihorn!
Saihorn!
A vain attempt.
I was born stronger than
any and all Pokémon living on this planet.
You can’t say that without fighting!
Do you volunteer?
What?
What was that?
What, meow?
“Mew”?
All humans who aspire to become Pokémon Trainers
wish to begin with...
...Fushigidane,
Zenigame,
or Hitokage.
And these are my creations;
their evolved forms...
...copied.
Copied?
A battlefield?
You mean you want to have
a Pokémon Battle?
I have my Fushigibana, Bernard!
And I have my Kamex, Exex!
Me, too!
Lizardon, I choose you!
Lizardon, no surprise attacks!
Quite an ill-mannered Lizardon.
Who will face us first?
I let my guard down earlier,
but that won’t happen again!
Go, Bernard!
Use Leaf Cutter!
Vine Whip.
Energy Ball!
All right!
Leaf Storm.
Bernard!
Are you okay?!
I’m next!
Go, Exex!
Rocket Headbutt!
Rocket Headbutt.
Exex! Hydro Pump!
Exex!
Satoshi, be careful!
Their moves are really powerful!
I know!
As long as none of them land,
it doesn’t matter!
Let’s go, Lizardon!
We’ll fight back with speed!
How is that
“fighting back with speed”?
His opponent is too fast!
Lizardon!
Globe Throw.
It seems to lack
both speed and power.
Exex!
Bernard!
Do you plan to
steal people’s Pokémon?!
“Steal”?
No...
I will create far superior copies of
the Pokémon you’re so proud of! Ones befitting of me!
Copies?!
Cut it out!
That’s against the rules!
Don’t give me orders!
I make my own rules.
Here they come!
Run, everyone!
Gyarados!
Hey!
I just gotta return them
to their own Balls!
How pointless.
Return, Zenigame, Fushigidane!
Right!
How is that...?
Nothing is impossible
for these Monster Balls I’ve created.
Stay quiet!
Oh, no!
Koduck!
Rokon!
Run, Pikachu!
Pikachu!
Don’t give up!
Who’s this?
Strike!
Dugong!
Rafflesia!
Sandpan!
Nidoqueen!
Showers!
But this is definitely Nyarth, meow...
Oww...
Brat boy?!
Team Rocket?!
Sorry, but I don’t have
time for this today!
Hang on!
Hey!
Who’s this?
Pikachu?!
Come on...!
Oh, my!
Pikachu!
So many copies!
They’re coming out...
My copy, too!
Those are all copies?!
Oh, my! Here come
the real ones, too!
Zenigame!
Fushigidane!
Humans!
I will not take your lives.
You are free to leave.
That is, if you’re capable of
braving the storm...
What is happening?
Unforgivable...
I’ll never forgive you!
Satoshi!
Koduck!
Rokon!
Did you free them?
I’ll protect my Pokémon...
Protect my friends!
Satoshi!
Stop!
What?
What is that?
A Pokémon?
Mew!
I’ve seen pictures of it
in books...
So have I.
The phantom Pokémon...
Mew...
The mightiest Pokémon, Mew,
said to be one of a kind!
Mew?
It really exists!
Yes.
Yet I am the mightiest Pokémon.
It is true that I was
created from you...
...but I am the stronger one!
I am the real one!
Mew and Mewtwo...
Mewtwo was created
from Mew...
Only I will survive!
Why do you retreat?
Do you avoid battle out of fear?
It appears you can
fight back, at least.
It’s time to determine who is real!
Am I stronger than Mew?
Are we stronger than
you so-called originals?
We were created to
surpass you in strength!
So that’s it, meow.
What’s it saying?
“The originals won’t lose.
“Real is real. If they battle with physical strength alone
rather than using their moves,
“the real Pokémon will not
lose to mere copies.”
“Real is real,” you say?
Very well.
We can determine who is real
without our moves!
We are the stronger ones!
Go!
What kind of a battle is this?
Real or copy...
They’re all still alive!
They’re all living creatures.
Even though they’re artificial,
they’re still living, breathing creatures.
Real ones and copies...
But both living creatures...
Neither is “winning” this fight.
If you ask us about this...
I just don’t know...
This is really depressing...
It’s like they’re
bullying themselves...
It’s like looking at
my past self...
Like looking at
my current self...
What an awful feeling!
You’re...!
These gotta hurt, meow...
All the other Pokémon are fighting,
so don’t be such a coward, meow!
What?
“You’re the coward,” meow?
“Why won’t you fight me”?!
“Those claws must hurt”?
Your claws gotta hurt way more, meow!
“I bet the moon
is round tonight”?
Yeah...
It’s gotta be a full moon, meow.
Talking about the moon
at a time like this...
You’re quite the philosopher, meow...
Pikachu!
Oww...
That’s enough!
Stop!
Satoshi!
I have to make them stop...
You can’t.
Unless Mew and Mewtwo stop,
the fighting will continue.
Living creatures never yield their territory
to others of their kind.
Oh, no...
They’ll fight until they’ve
driven their foes away.
That’s what living creatures do.
That’s what living creatures do...
But Mewtwo was created by humans.
But... now it’s just like
any other creature.
Now...
just like any other creature...
Mew and Mewtwo...
And Pikachu...
And the other Pikachu, too...
Please, just stop!
Stop!
Satoshi!
Impossible!
A human attempted to
end our battle?
Satoshi...
Pikachu...
Pikachu!
Indeed...
As it stands, you and I are both
Pokémon who came to exist in this world.
It may be best that no one
know of this incident.
Perhaps it is best left forgotten.
Where are you all going?
We have been born...
We are alive.
We will live on...
...somewhere... in this world.
Please quiet down, everyone!
We can’t send out any ships
in this storm!
Never before have I witnessed
a hurricane of such ferocity.
Please, seek shelter.
Man, what a letdown...
There’s no need to worry.
We’re opening the Pokémon Center
to be used as a shelter.
Anyone who wishes to use our services,
please come with me.
Ms. Joy, Ms. Junsa, Ms. Voyager...
All three of them look stunning today,
drenched in rain...
But... what are we doing here?
Not sure...
We’re just... here, I guess.
Well, whatever.
Is this even possible?
The hurricane...
It’s like it never happened...
Yeah...
I’d say the ships can
set sail tomorrow.
Yes.
Is that...?
What?
I think it was...
I don’t see anything.
Just a bunch of clouds.
The day I set off to become a Pokémon Master,
I saw a phantom Pokémon.
And I think I just saw another.
Maybe you’ll get to
meet another one!
A phantom Pokémon.
Yeah!
I’m sure someday I will!
Pocket Monsters...
Pokémon for short.
This is the tale of those aiming
to become Pokémon Trainers,
and their encounters with
the strange creatures known as Pokémon.
Their journey will go on and on.
You know,
with this island being deserted and all...
It’s kinda refreshing!
A nice change of pace!
Somehow, this is a really...
...great feeling!
aruki tsuzukete doko made yuku no
How much farther will you walk?
kaze ni tazunerarete tachidomaru
The wind calls out, and you come to a halt
hitotsume no taiko tokun to natte
The first beat made a resounding thump
tatta hitotsu no inochi hajimatta
as a single life began
yagate nanika o motomete
Before long, you unfurled your little hands
chiisana te no hira o hiroge
in search of something unknown
kimi wa sugu ni mitsuketa ne
Before long, you discovered
kimi janai dareka o
another besides yourself
tanjoubi iwau rousoku fueta kedo
Though you've added more candles to celebrate your birth,
tatta hitotsu no furusato tabidatta
and you've left your one and only hometown behind,
ima mo nanika o motomete
still, you seek the unknown,
ookina hitomi kagayaite
your wide-eyed gaze shines bright
kimi no poketto no naka ni wa
Contained within your pockets
kimi janai dareka to no...
lie memories you share with someone else...
ikutsumo no deai
Innumerable meetings
ikutsumo no wakare
Innumerable farewells
maboroshi no you na omoide mo sukoshi
And precious few dreamlike moments
aruki tsuzukete doko made yuku no
How much farther will you walk?
Shogakukan 12 magazines
illustration contest
Shogakukan 12 magazines art contest
Winners
Monthly Corocoro Comics
Beppu Kanon - Aichi
Corocoro Ichiban!
Reon Yamazaki - Tokyo
Corocoro Aniki
Yamaoka Nami - Hiroshima
kaze ni tazunerarete sora o miru
The wind calls out, and you gaze toward the sky
Weekly Shonen Sunday
Ishikawa Sho - Kanagawa
Pokémon Fan
Kakuta Miyuki - Saitama
Shogaku Ichinensei
Nakashima Mai - Toyama
aruki tsuzukete doko made yukou ka
How much farther will we walk together?
Yochien
Masumoto Yuuki - Yamaguchi
Televi-Kun
Ookawa Ren - Osaka
Chao
Iha Reina - Okinawa
Pucchigumi
Oozawa Kaho - Okayama
kaze to issho ni mata aruki dasou
Together with the wind, we will set out once again
Sunday Web Every x pixiv
Tsuchi - Hiroshima
Shogakukan Kids
Suzuki Keita - Saitama
daichi fumishime doko made mo yukou
Stepping out onto the road, let us go on and on
mezashita ano yume o tsukamu made
Until we seize that sought after dream
daichi fumishime doko made mo yukou
Stepping out onto the road, let us go on and on
mezashita ano yume o tsukamu made
Until we seize that sought after dream